## Ian Dexter D. Marquez

### DevOps engineer

+63 917 887 6260 im@iandexter.net https://www.iandexter.net

With more than 10 years extensive experience in administering Linux and Unix platforms. Develops and maintains various automation tools for infrastructure management and application deployment. Collaborates with global software development and operations teams in application delivery and support. Certified in Red Hat Enterprise Linux, Microsoft Windows, and ITIL Foundation in IT Service Management.

#### **QUALIFICATIONS**

# Bachelor of Science in Computing major in Computer Science, 2011

Technological University of the Philippines, Manila

**Red Hat Certified Engineer**, OCTOBER 2008 (NOT CURRENT)

ITIL v3 Foundation in IT Service Management, JULY 2008

**Red Hat Certified Technician**, November 2006

Microsoft Certified Professional, May 2006

Trend Micro Certified Security Expert, June 2006

#### Interests

DevOps, Amazon Web Services, OpenShift, OpenStack, Google Cloud Platform, PaaS, IaaS

#### Skill areas

- Unix/Linux systems administration (16 years / advanced)
- Infrastructure automation (8 years / proficient)
- Application deployment and support (11 years / advanced)
- Network design, development and administration (5 years / proficient)
- Web design, development and management (3 years / proficient)
- Identity management (2 years / proficient)

#### Languages

- Bash (16 years / advanced)
- Perl (9 years / proficient)
- PHP (3 years / proficient)
- Python (6 years / proficient)
- SQL (2 years / proficient)
- JavaScript (7 years / proficient)

#### **Platforms**

- Red Hat Enterprise Linux, CentOS, Fedora (16 years / advanced)
- SuSE Linux Enterprise Server (3 years / advanced)
- Ubuntu, Debian (6 years / proficient)
- Sun Solaris, IBM AIX (1 year / basic)
- Microsoft Windows 2003 Server (1 year / basic)

#### EXPERIENCE

#### Senior DevOps engineer

**DECEMBER 2015 TO PRESENT** 

*CompareGlobalGroup* 

Heads the distributed team that handles the maintenance and operation of the organization's cloud infrastructure. CompareGlobalGroup is the most comprehensive financial comparison platform in the world, with presence in Asia, Europe and Latin America.

#### **DevOps engineer (part-time)**

NOVEMBER 2014 TO NOVEMBER 2015

CompareGlobalGroup

Part of the global team that created and upgraded the organization's cloud infrastructure. CompareGlobalGroup is the most comprehensive financial comparison platform in the world, with presence in Asia, Europe and Latin America.

#### Linux system administrator

APRIL 2010 TO DECEMBER 2015

Asian Development Bank (under RCG IT, Inc.)

Developed and maintained automation tools to manage the Unix infrastructure for the Bank's mission-critical applications like ERP, data warehousing, financials, and business intelligence. The Asian Development Bank is a multilateral financial institution that provides technical and financial assistance to developing countries.

#### Senior software engineer

MAY 2007 TO APRIL 2010

Accenture, Inc.

Supported the global directory services, identity management, and web infrastructure of a leading financial services firm. Accenture is an industry leader in global management consulting, technology services, and outsourcing.

#### Unix system administrator

JANUARY 2007 TO APRIL 2007

Asian Development Bank (under Cytronics, Inc.)

Operated and maintained Unix servers in the Bank's data center. The Asian Development Bank is a multilateral financial institution that provides technical and financial assistance to developing countries.

#### Systems engineer

APRIL 2006 TO JANUARY 2007

Trend Micro, Inc.

Provided intermediate-level technical and engineering support for Trend Micro enterprise products as part of its EMEA Technical Support Center infrastructure. Trend Micro is a global leader in anti-virus and security solutions, providing comprehensive enterprise-level services across multiple platforms and customer segments.

#### Linux and web administrator

JULY 2004 TO MARCH 2006

Philippine Rice Research Institute

#### Network administrator

APRIL 2002 TO JULY 2004

National Irrigation Administration

## Community relations / information assistant

FEBRUARY 1999 TO MARCH

National Irrigation Administration

Last update: 10 September 2018